TALAL ABID

ELECTRICAL ENGINEER

CONTACT -

PHONE

+92323-4002153

MAIL

TALALABID@HOTMAIL.COM

ADDRESS

35-F MODEL TOWN LAHORE **PAKISTAN**

LINKEDIN

WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/TA-LAL-ABID-04291A165

SKILLS

VERBAL & NON VERBAL COMMUNICATION **SKILLS**

ORGANIZATION SKILLS

ABILITY TO MANAGE STRESS

DESIRE FOR SELF DEVELOPMENT AND LEARNING FROM **EXPERIENCES**

SOFTWARES

PROTEUS

MULTISIM

MS POWER POINT

MS WORD

PROFILE

I AM AN ELECTRICAL ENGINEER GRADUATED FROM GOVERNMENT COLLEGE UNIVER-SITY, LAHORE (GCU). I HAVE THE ABILITY TO APPLY THE SKILLS AND EXPERTISE TO GE-NERATE SOLUTIONS THAT REQUIRE DEVELOPMENT OF NEW IMPROVED TECHNIQUES AND PROCEDURES. ALONG WITH THAT I CAN CARRY OUT MANAGEMENT RELATED PROGRAMS EFFECTIVELY.

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2018-JUNE 2018 INTERNEE AT PAK ELEKTRON LIMITED (PEL)

WORKED IN SWITCH GEAR DEPARTMENT AND PRACTICALLY WITNESSED THE MANU-FACTURING AND TESTING OF A SWITCH GEAR. VISITED AND OBSERVED THE WORKING PROCEDURES OF FOLLOWING DEPART-

- (I) CURRENT AND POTENTIAL TRANSFORMER,
- (II) COMPUTER NUMERICAL CONTROL, (III) PAINT

JULY 2017-AUGUST 2017 INTERNEE AT NATIONAL TRANSMISSION AND DESPATCH COMPANY

WORKED IN PROTECTION AND CONTROL DEPARTMENT AND VISITED GRID STATIONS IN ORDER TO WITNESS THE PRACTICAL APPLICATION OF OUR

KNOWLEDGE.

JUNE 2012 INTERNEE AT SHAUKAT KHANUM MEMORIAL CANCER HOSPITAL

WORKED AS A VOLUNTEER IN THE PATHOLOGY DEPARTMENT AND HELPED THE STAFF MEMBERS IN ORGANIZING THE RECORDS OF PATIENTS.

JUNE 2010 INTERNEE AT WORLD WILD LIFE FEDERATION (WWF)

WORKED AS A REPRESENTATIVE AND CONDUCTED AWARENESS CAMPAIGNS TO SAFE WILD LIFE. OFFERED MEMBERSHIPS TO THE PEOPLE.

EDUCATION

NOVEMBER 2014-IUNE 2018 OOVERNMENT COLLEGE UNIVERSITY LAHORE

B.SC ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

NON INVASIVE BLOOD GLUCOSE METER AS FINAL YEAR PROJECT: THIS PROJECT INVOLVES THE DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT OF AN APPARATUS THROUGH WHICH ONE CAN MEASURE THE BLOOD GLUCOSE LEVEL WITHOUT INVA-SION.

OBSTACLE AVOIDANCE ROBOTIC VEHICLE:

A ROBOTIC VEHICLE WAS DESIGNED WHICH AUTOMATICALLY DETECTS A HURDLE USING ULTRASONIC SENSORS AND TAKES AN ALTERNATIVE PATH.

AUTOMATIC STREET LIGHT SWITCHING

IN THIS PROJECT A PCB CIRCUIT WAS DESIGNED THAT CAN AUTOMATICALLY TURN ON AND TURN OFF A STREET LIGHT USING A LIGHT DEPENDENT RESISTOR.

2012-2014 BEACONHOUSE SCHOOL SYSTEM

A'LEVELS

50% SCHOLARSHIP WAS AWARDED

SCORED 3B

SCIENTIA 2013:

ORGANIZED PAKISTAN'S BIGGEST SCIENCE OLYMPIAD HOSTED BY BEACONHOUSE DE-FENCE LAHORE AND RECEIVED LETTER OF APPRECIATION FROM ADMINISTRATION.

2009-2012 BEACONHOUSE SCHOOL SYSTEM GARDEN TOWN CAMPUS

O'I EVELS SCORED 3A* 3A.2B BRONZE MEDAL WAS AWARDED FOR OBTAINING 6AS

EXTRA CURRICULLAR ACTIVITIES AND AWARDS

PLATINUM AWARD IN MATHLETICS BY UNICEF IN 2011

ATTAINED POSITION IN THE T.V. QUIZ MIND GRIND WITH DEREK O BRIEN

HEAD BOY OF BEACONHOUSE SCHOOL SYSTEM PECO ROAD BRANCH

RECEIVED VARIOUS CERTIFICATES ON ACHIEVING GOOD POSITIONS IN EXTRA-CURRI-CULAR ACTIVITIES CONDUCTED WITHIN AND OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL PREMISES.